CRAIG NEESON

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



102 The Lucas Building, Belfast, Co. Antrim BT2 8HB

Contact and Media

craigneeson@hotmail.co.uk 07517099522

www.zestyacid.com https://uk.linkedin.com/in/craig-neeson-





ABOUT

Experienced Full-Stack Developer with a demonstrated history of contributing to both large and small projects across Northern Ireland and the US. Skilled in front and back-end stacks with the primary focus of creating intuitive, engaging applications for the web.



EXPERIENCE

NITEC SOLUTIONS

Software Developer, November 2017—Present (10 months)

My most recent role with Nitec Solutions gave me the opportunity to play a pivotal part in redesigning many of the deployment and front-end coding practises that the company employs to create its products. This involved implementing fully automated continuous integration pipelines, establishing private package registries for dependency management, and the creation of a fully modular front-end component system to enable efficient code reuse. In tandem with internal process development, I of course was still involved heavily in delivering quality, fully bespoke solutions to the Nitec customer base.

LIBERTY INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Associate Software Engineer, June 2017— November 2017 (6 months)

My graduate position on an integrations team from LIT allowed me to see how larger companies architect and deliver market-ready solutions to international clients. I worked in a self-lead, fully agile team to help build the highly scalable infrastructure for a brand new insurance product.

NITEC SOLUTIONS

Placement Developer, June 2015 — August 2016 (1 year 3 months)

My second placement position with Nitec Solutions was part of a four-year Computing course at Ulster University. My role in the company allowed me to work alongside seasoned enterprise developers on the .NET stack for small-to-medium sized businesses exclusively in Northern Ireland.

O'BRIENS IRISH SANDWICH BARS

Counter Assistant, February 2013 —June 2015 (2 years 5 months)

My duties varied greatly from barista-work to food prep, the busy environment suited me well as I (along with my coworkers) found satisfaction in providing a smooth, quality service to customers on a daily basis.

GALGORM RESORT & SPA

Kitchen Porter, September 2012 — Febuary 2013 (6 months)

My first job in the hospitality industry allowed me to experience first-hand a busy kitchen service. The standards of highwork speed and strict quality-control are traits that have stuck with me ever since.

NITEC SOLUTIONS

Placement Student, July 2012 — August 2012 (2 months)

An initial unpaid placement with Nitec during my high-school summer months solidified my thoughts on pursuing a career in the ever evolving technology industry.



FRONT-END

My primary passion is front-end, I have extensive experience building rich, data-centric user experiences for the web using a variety of different tools and setups. I am up-to-date with the latest ES6 standard of JavaScript and am obsessive in my efforts to promote and champion the latest features of the language. I have experience with all of the baseline web technologies such as HTML/CSS and pre-processors like SCSS and LESS as well as standalone templating engines such as Pug and Handlebars. My hobbyist experience also includes the use of the latest JavaScript frameworks including Vue.js and React, state-based web frameworks like these are of great interest to me at this point in my career. I have also been responsible for configuring front-end build systems like Webpack, Gulp and Grunt.



BACK-END

I have most experience with the ASP.NET MVC stack in both .NET Framework and .NET Core projects. C# is the language that I have had most experience with but have also had exposure to Java and Kotlin in the setting of a microservice architecture. I have experience designing Continuous Integration and Delivery pipelines on both Microsoft's Visual Studio Team Services and Atlassian's Bamboo build and release systems.



INFRASTRUCTURE

Throughout my career I have had the opportunity to work on traditional monolithic architectures targeting on-premises IIS servers as well as the Azure Cloud. I have used many of the resources made available by the Azure Cloud to solve problems that would be difficult or inefficient to solve using traditional methods. Examples include providing enterprise-ready security by harnessing Azure Active Directory, implementing a delivery route planning dashboard using a customised version of Azure Maps, and providing secure storage of binary files in Blob Storage accounts. On the other side of the cloud, I have experience working with highly scalable microservice architectures comprised of resources from AWS. These technologies include Amazon Lambdas, SQS (queues), and SNS (messaging.)



PROJECTS

I have been fortunate enough to be involved in the creation and maintenance of web-apps for many industries across the country including systems for manufacture, healthcare and ecommerce. Most projects I have been part of are fully bespoke, tailored to the specific business-needs of the customer in question. I also have experience developing and continuously deploying products for the US insurance consumer markets.



EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ULSTER (2013-2017)

BSc Hons Computing with DPP Graduated with First Class Honours

CAMBRIDGE HOUSE GRAMMAR SCHOOL (2006-2013)

A-Level ICT B - Technology & Design B - English Literature D

GCSE ICT A - Technology & Design B - English Literature B

English Language B - Art B - Math C - Statistics C

Physics C - Spanish C - Religious Studies C